<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ASCII"?>
<!--
 Fabric3
 Copyright (c) 2009-2013 Metaform Systems

Fabric3 is licensed under modified terms of the GNU General
Public License. See the accompanying license file for details.
 -->
<definitions
        xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/opencsa/sca/200912"
        xmlns:sca="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/opencsa/sca/200912"
        xmlns:f3="urn:fabric3.org"
        targetNamespace="http://docs.oasis-open.org/ns/opencsa/sca/200912">

    <intent name="serverAuthentication" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            Communication through the binding requires that the server is authenticated by the client
        </description>
        <qualifier name="transport" default="true"/>
        <qualifier name="message"/>
    </intent>

    <intent name="clientAuthentication" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            Communication through the binding requires that the client is authenticated by the server
        </description>
        <qualifier name="transport" default="true"/>
        <qualifier name="message"/>
    </intent>

    <intent name="authentication" requires="clientAuthentication">
        <description>
            A convenience intent to help migration
        </description>
        <qualifier name="transport" default="true"/>
        <qualifier name="message"/>
    </intent>

    <intent name="mutualAuthentication" requires="clientAuthentication serverAuthentication">
        <description>
            Communication through the binding requires that the
            client and server to authenticate each other
        </description>
    </intent>

    <intent name="confidentiality" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            Communication through the binding prevents unauthorized users from reading the messages
        </description>
        <qualifier name="transport" default="true"/>
        <qualifier name="message"/>
    </intent>

    <intent name="integrity" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            Communication through the binding prevents tampering with the messages sent between the client and the service.
        </description>
        <qualifier name="transport" default="true"/>
        <qualifier name="message"/>
    </intent>

    <intent name="authorization" constrains="sca:implementation" intentType="implementation">
        <description>
            Ensures clients are authorized to use services.
        </description>
        <qualifier name="fineGrain" default="true"/>
    </intent>

    <bindingType name="f3:binding.local"
                 mayProvide="sca:asyncInvocation sca:noListener sca:propagatesTransaction sca:transactedOneWay sca:confidentiality sca:integrity sca:atLeastOnce sca:atMostOnce sca:exactlyOnce sca:ordered sca:SOAP sca:SOAP.1_1 sca:SOAP.1_2 sca:SOAP.v1_1 sca:SOAP.v1_2"/>

    <bindingType name="sca:binding.sca" mayProvide="sca:oneWay sca:confidentiality sca:integrity sca:atLeastOnce sca:atMostOnce sca:exactlyOnce sca:ordered"/>

    <!-- Reliable messaging related intents -->
    <intent name="atLeastOnce" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            This intent is used to indicate that a message sent by a client is always delivered to the component.
        </description>
    </intent>

    <intent name="atMostOnce" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            This intent is used to indicate that a message that was successfully sent by a client is not delivered more than once to the component.
        </description>
    </intent>

    <intent name="exactlyOnce" requires="atLeastOnce atMostOnce" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            This profile intent is used to indicate that a message sent by a client is always delivered to the component. It also indicates that
            duplicate messages are not delivered to the component.
        </description>
    </intent>

    <intent name="ordered" appliesTo="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            This intent is used to indicate that all the messages are delivered to the component in the order they were sent by the client.
        </description>
    </intent>

    <!-- Transaction related intents -->
    <intent name="managedTransaction" excludes="sca:noManagedTransaction" mutuallyExclusive="true" constrains="sca:implementation" intentType="implementation">
        <description>
            A managed transaction environment is necessary in order to run the component. The specific type of managed transaction needed is
            not constrained.
        </description>
        <qualifier name="global" default="true">
            <description>
                For a component marked with managedTransaction.global a global transaction needs to be present before dispatching any method on the
                component - using any transaction propagated from the client or else beginning and completing a new transaction.
            </description>
        </qualifier>
        <qualifier name="local">
            <description>
                A component marked with managedTransaction.local needs to run within a local transaction containment (LTC) that is started and ended
                by the SCA runtime.
            </description>
        </qualifier>
    </intent>

    <intent name="noManagedTransaction" excludes="sca:managedTransaction" constrains="sca:implementation" intentType="implementation">
        <description>
            A component marked with noManagedTransaction needs to run without a managed transaction, under neither a global transaction nor
            an LTC. A transaction propagated to the hosting SCA runtime is not joined by the hosting runtime on behalf of a component marked with
            noManagedtransaction.
        </description>
    </intent>

    <intent name="transactedOneWay" excludes="sca:immediateOneWay" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="implementation">
        <description>
            For a reference marked as transactedOneWay any OneWay invocation messages are transacted as part of a client global transaction.
            For a service marked as transactedOneWay any OneWay invocation message are received from the transport binding in a transacted fashion,
            under the service?s global transaction.
        </description>
    </intent>

    <intent name="immediateOneWay" excludes="transactedOneWay" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="implementation">
        <description>
            For a reference indicates that any OneWay invocation messages are sent immediately regardless of any client transaction.
            For a service indicates that any OneWay invocation is received immediately regardless of any target service transaction.
        </description>
    </intent>

    <intent name="propagatesTransaction" excludes="suspendsTransaction" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            A service marked with propagatesTransaction is dispatched under any propagated (client) transaction and the service binding
            needs to be capable of receiving a transaction context. A reference marked with propagatesTransaction propagates any
            transaction context under which the client runs when the reference is used for a request-response interaction and the
            binding of a reference marked with propagatesTransaction needs to be capable of propagating a transaction context.
        </description>
    </intent>

    <intent name="suspendsTransaction" excludes="propagatesTransaction" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            A service marked with suspendsTransaction is not dispatched under any propagated (client) transaction.
            A reference marked with suspendsTransaction does not propagate any transaction context under which the client runs when the
            reference is used.
        </description>
    </intent>

    <intent name="managedSharedTransaction" requires="managedTransaction.global propagatesTransaction">
        <description>
            Used to indicate that the component requires both the managedTransaction.global and the propagatesTransactions intents
        </description>
    </intent>

    <!-- Miscellaneous intents -->
    <intent name="asyncInvocation" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            Indicates that request/response operations for the interface of this wire are "long running" and must be treated as two separate message
            transmissions
        </description>
    </intent>

    <intent name="SOAP" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            Specifies that the SOAP messaging model is used for delivering messages.
        </description>
        <qualifier name="1_1"/>
        <qualifier name="1_2"/>
        <qualifier name="v1_1" default="true"/>
        <qualifier name="v1_2"/>
    </intent>

    <intent name="JMS" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            Requires that the messages are delivered and received via the JMS API.
        </description>
    </intent>

    <intent name="noListener" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            This intent can only be used on a reference. Indicates that the client is not able to handle new inbound connections. The binding
            and callback binding are configured so that any response or callback comes either through a back channel of the connection from the
            client to the server or by having the client poll the server for messages.
        </description>
    </intent>

    <sca:intent name="EJB" constrains="sca:binding" intentType="interaction">
        <sca:description>
            Specifies that the EJB API is needed to communicate with the service or reference.
        </sca:description>
    </sca:intent>

    <policySet name="allowsPassByReferencePolicy" provides="f3:allowsPassByReference">
        <f3:allowsPassByReferencePolicy/>
    </policySet>

    <intent name="f3:allowsPassByReference" constrains="sca:implementation" intentType="interaction">
        <description>
            Used to indicate the implementation allows pass-by-reference semantics.
        </description>
    </intent>


</definitions>